# THERESA SMITH

# Data Analyst

(615) 613-2378 | tsmith0691@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

## **ABOUT ME**

Creative problem solver with the ability to think outside of the box. I had a career as a nurse for 10 years, and through that I developed valuable skill sets. I'm detail oriented and I love collaborating with teammates. As a nurse I was constantly assessing situations in various practical ways, and those assessments drove my decisions regarding patient care. I realized I could make a career change. Data has always intrigued me, because I love telling stories and because data informs everything we do. I know I can use the skills I've learned to be a storyteller through data analysis.

#### **SKILLS**

- Excel (Pivot tables, PowerPivot add-on)
- SQL (PostgreSQL)
- Git/GitHub

- Power BI
- Agile Methodology
- Kanban Boards

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Nashville Software School Data Analyst Apprentice

September 2022- Present

Intensive full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

# **PROJECTS**

Nashville City Cemetery | Excel

Utilized Excel to clean and analyze data on burials at the Nashville City Cemetery from 1846 to 1979. Information found was used to create marketing materials for the cemetery. Created visualizations on age at death by race, number of burials by year, common causes of death, and more.

Wine Enthusiast Magazine Reviews | Power BI

Loaded a dataset from kaggle.com for analysis of 130k wine reviews. Deployed a <u>dashboard</u> to showcase details about varieties of wine including average price, score, and country of production.

Lahman Baseball | Team Project | SQL

Used a dataset of 20 tables to analyze baseball statistics, which required the use of joins, case statements, subqueries, and common table expressions.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Commented [1]: Great job! No changes needed, you can go ahead and upload this to the v3 folder, you are application ready!

Commented [2R1]: Thank you!

#### **Registered Nurse**

# May 2012- September 2022

(Brentwood Surgery Center, St. Thomas Hospital for Specialty Surgery, Urology Surgery Center, Nashville Endosurgery Center, Southern Hills Medical Center, St. Thomas West Hospital)

- Provided direct quality care to patients including daily monitoring, recording, and evaluating treatment of various medical conditions
- Safe administration of medications with appropriate documentation
- Worked in a hospital setting and ambulatory surgery setting
- Collaborated with members of the healthcare team to achieve better patient outcomes
- Worked as a charge nurse: providing staff guidance, supporting challenging situations, and implementing urgent policies and procedures
- Used computer charting systems such as Cerner, MEDITECH, Provation

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Nashville Software School - Nashville, TN

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certificate

January 2023- Expected Graduation Date

#### Columbia State Community College - Franklin, TN

Associate of Applied Science in Nursing

May 2012

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Licensure, Registered Nurse, State of Tennessee, License number 187810 (ex. 06/30/2023)

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

BLS, ACLS

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Ekisa Ministries, Jinja, Uganda (September 2014-November 2014)

- Managed the medical care at a home for children with special needs
- Aided in the diagnosis and treatment of malaria